Guide to the Sherman Kent Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1920-1980; Series I; 7.75; (19 boxes)
  - Denny, Frank, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Classified (Box 60)
  - Destler, Chester, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Dillard, Hardy C., 1943-1952, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Dodd, Edward H., Jr., 1941-1951, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 91-92)
  - Dulles, Allen W., 1952-1968 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Dunham, William Huse, Jr., 1944-1972 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - E (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Earle, Edward Mead (Box 4, Folder 95)
    See: box 7, folder 178
  - Elizabethan Club, 1931-1935, 1942, 1964, 1971-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 96-97)
  - Ellsworth, John E., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - England, Richard, 1959-1969 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Evans, Allan, 1947-1968 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Evenson, Marvin P., 1947-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Ewing, Gifford C., 1938, 1950-1957, 1966-1967, 1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Fa-Fl (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Fo (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Fr-Fu (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - F. S. Crofts & Co., Publishers, 1941, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Foord, Archibald, 1937-1954, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 107-108)
  - Ford, Franklin L., 1945-1969 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Ford, Harold, 1965-1974, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Classified (Box 60)
  - Ford Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    See also: box 2, folder 53
  - Foreign Affairs, 1946, 1952-1968 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - France. Archives Nationales and Archives Départementales, 1934, 1937, 1968-1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 114-115)
    See also: box 2, folder 33
  - French, Lindol R., 1970, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - French Historical Studies, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    See also: box 14, folder 300-301
  - Friends Alumni Association (Sidwell Friends School), 1973-1980 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Furniss, Edgar S. (Box 5, Folder 118)
    See: box 18, folder 400-401
  - Furuya, Toru, 1959-1970 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Ga-Gi (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Gl-Gu (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Gehlen, Reinhard, 1961-1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Gilbert, Felix, 1950-1952, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Gilliat and Company, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Gleason, Madeline R., 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 125-131)
  - Goodpaster, Andy, 1969, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Grabo, Cynthia, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1934-1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Gruenter, Alfred M., 1947-1953 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Ha (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - He-Hi (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Ho (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Hu (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Harbison, E. Harris, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Harmer, Bernard D., 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Harris, William R., 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Hart, Betty and Marvin, 1973-1979, undated (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company, 1962-1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Harvard University, 1950-1952, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    See also: box 5, folder 125-131 box 6, folder 143 box 6, folder 163 box 12, folder 266 box 13, folder 294 box 18, folder 392
  - Harvard University Press, 1974-1976, undated (Box 6, Folder 147)
    See also: box 5, folder 125-131 box 18, folder 392
  - Hechinger, John W., 1961-1974 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Hellman, Geoffrey (Box 6, Folder 148)
    See: box 13, folder 287
  - Helms, Richard, 1965-1980 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Hemingway, Samuel B., 1941-1950 (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - Henning, Basil Duke and Alison, 1963, 1966-1968, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Henri Stern Watch Agency, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Hilgard, Galen Kent Howard, 1949-1959, 1969, 1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Hill, Harry W., 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Hoaver, Ed, 1945-1950 (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Hodgins, William P., 1962-1967, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - Hooker, Robert G., 1948, 1965-1979 (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - Hoover, Calvin B., 1951-1967 (Box 6, Folder 158)
  - Horton, Philip (Box 6, Folder 158)
    See: box 14, folder 315
  - Howard, Adaline Kent, 1933-1949, 1951-1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 159-160)
  - Howard, L. O., 1932-1934 (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Howard, Robert B., 1942, 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 162)
  - Hughes, Stuart H., 1945, 1950, 1968-1973 (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1959-1972 (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - Hunter, Robert and Caroline, 1944-1950, 1962, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Hunter, Miller & Fleming (Hunter, Turrell & Dahl; Hunter & Turrell; Hunter, Miller, Fleming & Berry), 1942-1980 (Box 7, Folder 166-176)
  - I (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Institute for Advanced Study, 1947-1952, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Institute for Religious and Social Studies, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - J (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Classified (Box 60)
  - Jackson, Wayne G., 1971-1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1946-1964, 1974, undated (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Journal of Modern History, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Joyce, Robert P., 1961-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Ka-Kent (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Ker-Ky (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Keller, Albert G., 1936, 1944-1952 (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Kennedy, David A., 1950, 1960, undated (Box 8, Folder 188)
    See also: box 17, folder 384
  - Kent, Alice, 1942, 1964-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Kent, Clarence and family, 1962-1979 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Kent, Elizabeth Gregory, 1930-1945, 1950-1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 191-198)
  - Kent, Elizabeth Thacher, 1932-1952, undated (Box 9, Folder 199-205)
  - Kent, Roger, 1933-1959 (Box 9, Folder 206-213)
    See also: box 39, folder 1-13
  - Kent, Roger, 1960-1980, undated (Box 10, Folder 214-226)
  - Kent, Sherman T., 1960-1971 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Kent, Thomas and Anne, 1949-1979 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - Kent, William, 1920-1926 (Box 10, Folder 229)
  - Kent, William, Jr. and Sophia Morris Kent, 1933-1965, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 230-236)
  - Kent, William III, 1947, 1949, 1960, 1968, 1980, undated (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Kent Woodlands Company, 1959-1974, 1977-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 238-239)
  - Kerr, Chester (Box 11, Folder 238-239)
    See: box 18, folder 408
  - Keyes, Francis (Box 11, Folder 238-239)
    See: box 17, folder 384
  - Kip, William B., 1930-1957, 1961-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 240-246)
  - Knorr, Klaus, 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 247)
  - Krout, John A., 1947-1950 (Box 11, Folder 248)
  - La (Box 12, Folder 249)
  - Le-Li (Box 12, Folder 250)
  - Lo-Ly (Box 12, Folder 251)
  - Labaree, Leonard W., 1937-1948 (Box 12, Folder 252)
  - Langer, William L. and Rowena, 1943-1978 (Box 12, Folder 253)
  - Lanusse, Ernesto Jorge, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 254)
  - Lewis, Dudley C., 1962-1971 (Box 12, Folder 255)
  - Lewis, Wilmarth Sheldon, 1946-1959, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 256)
  - Library of Congress, 1943-1974 (Box 12, Folder 257)
  - Liebert, Herman W. (Box 12, Folder 257)
    See: box 18, folder 406-407
  - Linder, Harold F., 1960-1968, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 258)
  - Lossky, Andrew, 1942-1946 (Box 12, Folder 259)
  - Mac-Mc (Box 12, Folder 260)
  - Mack-Me (Box 12, Folder 261)
  - Mi (Box 12, Folder 262)
  - Mo-Mu (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - McAfee, Helen (Box 12, Folder 263)
    See: box 18, folder 399
  - McCaskey, William S. (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - McCone, John A., 1965-1971, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 264)
  - McCormack, Winthrop, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - McHenry, Dean E. (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - MacIver, R. M. (Box 12, Folder 265)
    See: box 7, folder 179
  - McKay, Donald C., 1936-1950 (Box 12, Folder 266)
  - McLean, Morton and Boustead, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 267)
  - Marshall, Andrew W., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 268)
  - Mathias, James F. (Box 12, Folder 268)
    See: box 7, folder 182
  - Matthias, Willard C., 1964-1965, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 269)
  - Mee Yee & Company, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 270)
  - Mendenhall, Thomas C., 1941-1946, undated (Box 13, Folder 271)
  - Miller, John Perry, 1963-1965 (Box 13, Folder 272)
  - Miner, Robert G., 1964-1972, undated (Box 13, Folder 273)
  - Minto & Wilkie, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 274)
  - Moe, Henry Allen (Box 13, Folder 274)
  - Moore, Ernest, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 275)
  - Mowry, George E., 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 276)
  - Mutual of Omaha Insurance Company, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 277)
  - Na-Ne (Box 13, Folder 278)
  - Ng-No (Box 13, Folder 279)
  - National Civil Service League, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 280)
  - National War College, 1946-1963, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 281-284)
  - New Haven. Registrar of Voters, 1958-1965 (Box 13, Folder 285)
  - New Haven Rotary Club, 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 286)
  - New Yorker, 1934, 1949, 1953-1959 (Box 13, Folder 287)
  - Newman, Edgar Leon, 1973-1977 (Box 13, Folder 288)
  - Nineteen Twenty-Five F Street Club, Inc., 1945, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 289)
  - North's Insurance Agency, 1963-1974 (Box 13, Folder 290)
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1941-1953 (Box 13, Folder 291)
  - O (Box 13, Folder 292)
  - Osato, Timothy, 1949-1950, 1962-1968 (Box 13, Folder 293)
  - Owen, David and Louise, 1945-1950, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 294)
  - Pa (Box 13, Folder 295)
  - Pd-Pi (Box 13, Folder 296)
  - Pl-Py (Box 13, Folder 297)
  - Picher, Oliver, 1962-1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 298)
  - Pierson, George Wilson, 1940-1950, 1960-1972 (Box 14, Folder 299)
  - Pinkney, David, 1947-1978, undated (Box 14, Folder 300-301)
  - Platt, Washington, 1950-1960 (Box 14, Folder 302)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1974 (Box 14, Folder 303)
  - Preston, Alexander, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 304)
  - Princeton University, 1945-1960 (Box 14, Folder 305)
  - Princeton University, Center of International Studies (Box 14, Folder 305)
    See: box 11, folder 247
  - Princeton University Press, 1949-1959, 1962-1969, 1977-1980, undated (Box 14, Folder 306-309)
  - Pruitt, Bill, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Ra-Re (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Rh-Ry (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Rabb, Theodore K., 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 313)
  - Ransom, Harry Howe, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 314)
  - Reporter, 1950-1954 (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - Ripley, Kenneth, 1971-1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 316)
  - Ripley, S. Dillon, 1960, 1964, 1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 317)
  - Roberts, Henry L., 1944-1961 (Box 14, Folder 318)
  - Robinson, Geriod T., 1947-1966 (Box 15, Folder 319-320)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., 1949, 1959, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 321)
  - Rowell, Henry T., 1941-1942, 1965, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 322)
  - Sa (Box 15, Folder 323)
  - Sc-Se (Box 15, Folder 324)
  - Sh (Box 15, Folder 325)
  - Si-Sm (Box 15, Folder 326)
  - Sn-Sp (Box 15, Folder 327)
  - St-Sw (Box 15, Folder 328)
  - Sawyer, John E., 1944-1951, 1958-1962, 1972-1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 329-330)
  - Schardt, Max and Mary, 1967-1980 (Box 15, Folder 331-332)
  - Schleifer, James T., 1965-1968, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 333)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1937-1949, 1969, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 334)
  - Shapiro, Gilbert, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 335)
  - Shoe String Press, Inc., 1965-1966, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 336)
  - Smith, Abbot E., 1965-1979 (Box 15, Folder 337)
  - Smith, Don, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 338)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1947-1967 (Box 15, Folder 339)
  - Society for French Historical Studies, 1968-1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 340)
  - Sontag, Raymond J., 1936-1968, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 341)
  - Speiser, Ephraim A., 1946-1965 (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Spitzer, Alan, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 343)
  - Stavrianos, Leften S., 1950, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 344)
  - Stewart, William S., 1964-1971 (Box 16, Folder 345)
  - Stoddard, Carlos F., 1955, 1965-1971 (Box 16, Folder 346)
  - Strayer, Joseph, 1960-1970, undated (Box 16, Folder 347)
  - Ta-Th (Box 16, Folder 348)
  - Ti-Ty (Box 16, Folder 349)
  - Teachers Insurance & Annuity Association, 1942, 1968-1974 (Box 16, Folder 350)
  - Terhune, Robert (Box 16, Folder 350)
    See: box 13, folder 290
  - Thacher, Anson S., 1937-1950, 1965-1980, undated (Box 16, Folder 351-352)
  - Thacher, Elizabeth, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 353)
  - Thacher School, 1937, 1948-1950, 1955-1972, undated (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Thorburn, James G., 1959-1967 (Box 16, Folder 355)
  - Tudesq, Andre-J., 1968-1972, undated (Box 16, Folder 356)
  - United N - United S (Box 16, Folder 357)
    - Classified (Box 60)
  - Univ-Ur (Box 16, Folder 358)
  - Union and New Haven Trust Company, 1941-1947 1960-1973 (Box 16, Folder 359)
  - United States
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1949, 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 360)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1947-1960, 1962-1977 (Box 16, Folder 361-364)
      - Classified (3 folders) (Box 60)
    - Civil Service Commission, 1943-1945, 1961-1977 (Box 17, Folder 365)
    - Defense Intelligence School, 1968-1974 (Box 17, Folder 366)
    - Department of State, 1945-1969 (Box 17, Folder 367)
    - Department of the Interior, 1962-1969 (Box 17, Folder 368)
    - Department of the Treasury, 1943, 1960-1972, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 369)
    - Internal Revenue Service (Box 17, Folder 369)
    - Naval Academy, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 370)
    - Office of Strategic Services, 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 371)
    - Senate, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 372)
    - Social Security Administration, 1961-1977 (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - War Department, 1942-1947 (Box 17, Folder 374)
  - University of California, Santa Cruz, 1963-1977 (Box 17, Folder 375)
  - V (Box 17, Folder 376)
  - Vandenberg, Hoyt S., 1946-1950 (Box 17, Folder 377)
  - Vassar College, 1960-1975 (Box 17, Folder 378)
  - Wa-We (Box 17, Folder 379)
  - Wh-Wi (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Wo-Ww (Box 17, Folder 381)
  - Wallace, Thomas C., 1980 (Box 17, Folder 382)
  - Washington, D.C., 1942-1946, 1965-1968, 1974-1978, undated (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Westminster School, 1959-1964 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - White, Lawrence K., 1959-1972 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Whitman, John and Maggie, 1966-1973 (Box 17, Folder 386)
  - Wiggin, Lewis M. (Box 17, Folder 386)
    See: box 15, folder 336
  - Wilkie, Leroy K. (Box 17, Folder 386)
    See: box 13, folder 274
  - Willard, Charles H., 1950-1972 (Box 17, Folder 387)
  - Wilson, Len, 1948-1949, undated (Box 17, Folder 388)
  - Winnacker, Rudolph A., 1944-1959, 1972, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 389)
  - Wisner, Frank G., 1962-1969 (Box 18, Folder 390)
    - Classified (Box 60)
  - Wolfers, Arnold, 1942-1947, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 391)
  - Wolff, Robert Lee, 1946-1950, 1970-1976 (Box 18, Folder 392)
  - Woodbury, Robert L., 1963-1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 393)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 394)
  - Wright, Gordon, 1951, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 395)
  - Wright, Jerauld, 1963-1974 (Box 18, Folder 396)
  - Y (Box 18, Folder 397)
  - Yale Alumni Fund, 1970-1980 (Box 18, Folder 398)
  - Yale Review, 1942-1953 (Box 18, Folder 399)
    See also: box 18, folder 391
  - Yale University
    See also: box 4, folder 94 box 6, folder 134 box 12, folder 252 box 13, folder 272 box 14, folder 299 box 15, folder 334 box 16, folder 346
    - General, 1934-1954, 1960-1978, undated (Box 18, Folder 400-401)
    - Art Gallery, 1964, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 402)
    - Berkeley College, 1949-1980 (Box 18, Folder 403)
      General
    - Class of 1926 and 1926s, 1947-1949, 1968-1980, undated (Box 18, Folder 404)
      See also box 2, folder 47
      See also: box 16, folder 345
      See also: box 17, folder 387
    - Graduate School, Division of General Studies, 1940-1941 (Box 18, Folder 405)
    - Library, 1934-1969, 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 406-407)
  - Yale University Press, 1937, 1945-1973 (Box 18, Folder 408)
  - Z (Box 18, Folder 409)
  - Unidentified
    - A, 1973, undated (Box 18, Folder 410)
    - B, 1945-1980, undated (Box 18, Folder 411)
    - C, 1940-1973, undated (Box 18, Folder 412)
    - D, 1967, 1973, undated (Box 18, Folder 413)
    - E-F, 1934-1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 414)
    - G, 1945-1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 415)
    - H, 1934-1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 416)
    - J, 1946-1972, undated (Box 19, Folder 417)
    - K-L, 1950-1972, undated (Box 19, Folder 418)
    - M, 1937, 1970, 1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 419)
    - N, 1938, 1971, 1979, undated (Box 19, Folder 420)
    - P, 1948, 1966-1972, undated (Box 19, Folder 421)
    - R, 1942, 1970-1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 422)
    - S, 1938, 1946-1953, 1979, undated (Box 19, Folder 423)
    - T, V, 1949, 1972, 1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 424)
    - W, 1947-1950, 1963-1971, undated (Box 19, Folder 425)
    - No name, 1947-1949, 1958-1963, 1969-1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 426)
- WRITINGS, 1930-1976, undated; Series II; 7.75; (19 boxes)
  The WRITINGS series is arranged in the following sections: Book reviews, Articles, Books-published, Books-unpublished, Speeches, and [Lecture notes?]. Within each section the writings are arranged in chronological order by date of publication, delivery, or for unpublished works by date of creation.
  - Book reviews
    - Driault, Edouard. L'Expédition de Crète… Douin, Georges. Mohamed Aly et…, Circa 1930 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Piquet, Victor. L'Algérie Francaise, Circa 1930 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Crofton, R. H. The Old Consulate at Zanzibar, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Maurain, Jean. Un Bourgeois Francais…, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Scott, Franklin D. Bernadotte and the Fall of Napoleon, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Aubry, Octave. St. Helena, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Starkie, Enid. Arthur Rimbaud in Abyssinia, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Gray, J. M. A History of the Gambia, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Teixeira de Mattos, Alexander. The Recollections of Alexis de Tocqueville, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Tully, Andrew. C.I.A. The Inside Story -- "A Bad Book by Andrew Tully", 1962 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Allen. F. L. Since Yesterday, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Assorted items, France, Algeria, 1948 revolution, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Articles
    - "Record's Art Exhibit Reveals Unusual Talent," Yale Daily News, 1934 February 28 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "Supplement Extraordinary" on the impending demise of the Yale fraternity system, Yale Literary Magazine, 1934 October (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "The Century of Progress Collection," Yale Library Gazette, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Yale War Collection, Circa 1940 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "War Collection," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1940 March 22 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - New York World's Fair Collection, Yale Library Gazette, 1941 January 13 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Library Gathers Official, Personal Documents on World War II," Yale Daily News, 1941 January 15 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - "Prospects for the National Intelligence Service," Yale Review, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Government documents and historical research, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "Declaration of the Rights of Man and Citizen," Great Expressions of Human Rights, 1949-1950 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      See also: box 37, folder 231
    - "How Effective Is Our Intelligence?," The Reporter, 1950 September 12 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "The Need for an Intelligence Literature," C.I.A. Office of Training, 1955 September (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Classified (Box 60)
    - "Estimates and Influence," Foreign Service Journal, 1969 April (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - "Electoral Lists of France's July Monarchy," French Historical Studies, 1971 Spring (Box 20, Folder 26-27)
    - "La Composition de l'Electorat de 1827," 96e Congrès National des Sociétés Savantes Toulouse; Paris, 1971, 1975, 1976, undated (Box 20, Folder 28-29)
    - The aim of strategic intelligence, undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - "A Crucial Estimate Relived", undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - "The Cuban Missile Crisis of 1962: Presenting the Photographic Evidence Abroad", undated (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - Classified (Box 60)
    - "Death of an Hypothesis", undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - Classified (Box 60)
    - "John Maudgridge Snowden Allison: 1888-1944", undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - "Words of Estimative Probability", undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Books Published
    - A Boy and a Pig, but Mostly Horses
      - Chapters I-VII, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 36-45)
      - "Augusta", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 46)
      - "Dolly", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 47)
      - "How to Catch a Chipmunk", 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 48)
      - "How to Catch a Chipmunk, Big Rainbow", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 49)
      - "Iron Point", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 50)
      - "Middle Yuba", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 51)
      - "Patrick Henry and Fred Sinclair", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 52)
      - "Sheep Ranch Creek I", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 53)
      - "Sheep Ranch Creek II", 1973 (Box 22, Folder 54)
      - "The End of the School Year" "Augusta" revisions "Iron Point" revisions, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 55)
      - Notes, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - The French Election of 1827
      - Research notes, 1968 April-May, 1968 October-Nov, 1969 April-Jun, 1969-1972 (Box 23, Folder 57-60)
      - Working papers, 1968, 1968 Mar, July-Sep, 1970 May, 1970 Aug, 1971 May (Box 23, Folder 61-66)
      - Working papers, 1971, 1968-1972, undated (Box 24, Folder 67-69)
      - Chapters 1-6, 1968-1974 (Box 24, Folder 70-75)
      - Chapters 7-9, 1968-1974 (Box 25, Folder 76-78)
      - Conclusion chapter; Bibliographical note, 1968-1974 (Box 25, Folder 79)
      - Maps, 1968-1974 (Box 25, Folder 80)
      - Chapters 1-8: second draft, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 81-87)
      - Pp. 3-527, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 88-93)
      - Index, [1972] (Box 26, Folder 94)
      - Pp. 1-302, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 95-98)
      - Pp. 303-453, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 99-100)
    - Strategic Intelligence for American World Policy
      - Chapters 1-4: first draft, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 101-105)
      - Chapters 6-7: preliminary draft (Box 27, Folder 106-108)
      - Chapter 7: rejected sections, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 109)
      - Chapters 8-9: outlines, preliminary draft, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 110-112)
      - Chapters 9-11: preliminary draft, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 113-118)
      - Chapters 1-11, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 119-129)
      - Appendix 1, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 130)
      - Chapters 1-5: second draft, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 131-135)
        See also: box 59, folder 1
      - Chapters 3-4: third draft, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 136-137)
      - Chapter 4: "Current Doctrine of Strategic Intelligence", undated (Box 29, Folder 138)
      - Chapters 1-12 Complete manuscript, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 139-140)
      - Appendix: not used, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 141)
      - Pages from intermediate manuscript, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 142)
      - Preface, introduction, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 143)
      - Preface, introduction, dedications, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 144)
      - Introduction, chapters 3, 4, 8, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 145)
      - Preface, Part I, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 146)
      - Part II, charts, appendices, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 147)
      - Manuscript, chapters 1-11, appendix, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 148-149)
      - Rejected pages from first manuscript, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 150)
      - "Carbon, front matter, unidentified trash", 1948 (Box 30, Folder 151)
      - Notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 152)
      - Ancillary material, Chapter IV, undated (Box 30, Folder 153)
      - Index, undated (Box 31, Folder 154)
      - "The Content of Strategic Intelligence: A Digest From Strategic Intelligence", 1949 (Box 31, Folder 155)
      - Unauthorized foreign edited version of Strategic Intelligence for American World Policy, 1963 October 11 (Box 31, Folder 156)
      - Second printing: notes, 1965, 1970, undated (Box 31, Folder 157)
    - Writing History
      - Complete draft, pp. 1-145, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 158-159)
      - Complete draft, pp. 1-227, [1941] (Box 31, Folder 160-161)
      - Complete draft, [1941] (Box 31, Folder 162)
      - "An Abbreviated Manual of Style and Usage", undated (Box 31, Folder 163)